# PHILLIP PATTERSON

■ phillip.s.patterson1@gmail.com ② philpatterson.io in /in/philpatt/ 〇 philpatt

### **SUMMARY**

I am a Seattle-based Web Developer proficient in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, jQuery, TML5, CSS3, Javascript, jQuery, React, NodeJS, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Django, AJAX, RESTful APIs, and Web Scraping. I have a desire to grow and continuously learn to strengthen my passion for creating. The knowledge I have acquired thus far, gives me the ability to build responsive, full-stack web applications. Having a strong background in analytical science, I have a lot of experience with the cohesion of technology, data-analysis and troubleshooting with efficiency in a team-oriented environment.

This should show impact and aptitude. Show growth/volume/measurements/countable/

## **EDUCATION**

#### **Castleton University**

BA Health Science 2013

# **EMPLOYMENT**

General Assembly, Full-Stack Web Developer

Nov 2017 - Current

Worked for 50-60 hour weeks for in an intensive, collaborative learning environment.

Used white-boarding and Agile techniques during project sprint runs

#### Aspenti Health,

Data Review Scientist/Confirmation Scientist

Aug 2016 - Nov 2017

Collect data acquired from LC/MS/GC instrumentation

Process data using Laboratory Information Managment Systems Utilize good laboratory practices in pre-analytical, analytical and post-analytical procedures.

Maintain a good working knowledge of lab instrumentation and standard operating procedures .

Troubleshoot instrumentation and investigate aberrant test results.

Performs routine maintenance and troubleshooting of equipment

Prepares standards and reagents as required

Assist other testing personnel, supervisors, laboratory director and COO as required

#### Mylan Technologies,

Quality Control Analytical Chemist

Aug 2014 - Aug 2016

Perform tests on raw materials, intermediates, blends, and finished products and/or those samples specific to assigned organization using

LC/MC instrumentation, troubleshoot instrumentation and investigate aberrant test results.

Review, process and interpret test results and ensure that they meet specifications and compile information into report form. Maintain instrument logbooks, laboratory worksheets, and all relevant documentation according to cGMP documentation practices.

Act as a resource to team members and other Chemists.

Perform analytical investigations by drafting Analytical Investigation Report text, performing action steps, and drawing justifiable conclusions based on data.

Calibrate laboratory equipment as necessary.

#### **University of Vermont Medical Center**,

Phlebotomist

Aug 2013 - Aug 2014

Obtain blood specimens using venipuncture and capillary collection from patients of all ages from newborn to child, adolescent, adult and geriatric

Work in multiple healthcare settings such as at inpatient sites, and outpatient sites

Chooses proper tools and techniques for each age group and situation in order to obtain optimum specimens while minimalizing discomfort and hazards for the patient

Organized work to efficiently obtain specimens at optimum times

Serves as liaison between the laboratory, patients, nurses, and physicians

Maintain a professional demeanor when placed in stressful situations

Assisted in training and orientation of new employees as requested

## **SKILLS**

HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, React, NodeJS, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Django, AJAX, RESTful APIs, Web Scraping

# **ACTIVITIES**

**Castleton Men's Lacrosse** 

Aug 2009 - May 2013

Nominated Captain in 2013

# VOLUNTEERING

Castleton Mentoring Program, Mentor

May 2010 - May 2013